## HEMANTH VASU

## LinkedIn: In/hemanthvasu

# CONTACT

91-9080124409

hemanthvasu23@gmail.com

Chennai , India

#### SKILLS

Arduino(embedded C)

Python

C++

AutoCAD

Fusion360(beginner)

Eagle(beginner)

#### EDUCATION

- Higher Secondary School Certificate (90%)(2021)
- B.Tech in Electrical and Electronics Engineering at VIT Chennai. (Pursuing 2nd year) CGPA - 8.2 / 10

### LANGUAGES

English (Advanced) Tamil (Advanced) Telugu (Speak)

## **PROJECTS**

- PCB for line follower with miniaturized version of Arduino Mega.
- Robotic Arm control using IMU and Flex Sensor.
- Quadruped
- Hexapod
- Quadcopter

#### **PROFILE**

Aspiring Robotics engineer with over 3 years of industrial experience in Python, C++, and electronic engineering. A competent communicator with a team-oriented personality and adept at picking up skills. Aiming to synergistically work towards a futuristic vision in robotics.

#### **COURSES AND INTERESTS**

2014 - 2016

Undertook courses of varying ranges of beginner as well as advanced levels of Robotics at **SP Robotics Pvt Ltd.** 

Participated in National level competition, Tathva'16 organised by NIT Calicut.

2017 - 2020

Participated in Multiple Competitions.

(Robo Race, Line follower, Robo soccer, RoboWar)

- Tathva'18, NIT Calicut.
- TechnoXian ChampionShip'18, Delhi.
- Robotex'19 Qualifiers, Mumbai.
- Robotex'19 International, Ahmedabad.
- Tathva'19, NIT Calicut.
- Robotixlab Championship '19, Chennai.
- ROBO Wars Event, IIT Madras

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 2018 - 2020 Intern at INRO Labs

- Led Other Students as a mentor to build race and soccer robots for competitions.
- Successfully presented Seminars on Arduino and C++ Programming at Anna University for Engineering Students.
- Conducted an Interactive Session on Electronics and Sensors for Children of TCS Employees at TCS.
- Built a surveillance Robot For the Chennai Police Department during the
  Pandemic
- · Built an Assistant Robot during my Internship Period at INRO LABS

#### 2022 - 2023 Embedded Developer, Spezar Tech

- Worked on developing an embedded board with built-in IMU, and other sensors.
- Developed content for a course on building micro-satellite.
- Conducted workshop on **Drone Building**.

## 2023 - Present Head Of Operations , Dreadnought Robotics

- Heading the junior members of a multidisciplinary team of 70 members working on 5 different types of robots with Level 2 autonomy.
- Led a squad of 8 members to build an ROV for TAC Challenge, Norway.
- Successfully debuted our first ROV in TAC Challenge, Norway.
- Heading the AUV Department on the build of our next AUV.

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

- Winner of International Space Science Challenge'22 in Space robotics category.
- 2nd Place in Line Follower event at Robotixlab ChampionShip'19.
- 2nd Place in Robo Race event at Robotixlab ChampionShip'19.
- 1st Place in Autonomous Sumo at Robotex'19 Qualifiers.
- 2nd Place in Autonomous Sumo at Robotex'19 International . Ahmedabad.
- 2nd Place in Robo Race at **Robotex'19 International** , Ahmedabad.
- 3rd Place in Robo Race at TechnoXian ChampionShip'18.